https://www.sarraf.com/privacy-policy/

Click Here To See
Items.
Convert mm to Inches
The Sarraf Jewelry privacy policy is your guarantee that any personal information you provide us will remain private. We ask for personal information so that we can provide you with a personal and customized shopping experience. Your personal information will never be sold to any third party for any reason. Sarraf Jewelry is committed to keeping your personal information private. Please review our privacy policy for more detail.
Privacy Commitment
At Sarraf Jewelry, we are committed to protecting your privacy. We promise to keep all the information that you share with us confidential. We only collect personal information from customers in order to process billing, fulfill orders, and provide a personal and customized shopping experience. We do not share your information with any outside parties.
How We Use The information We Gather
When placing an order, you provide your name, mailing address, telephone number, e-mail address, credit card number, and expiration date. For customers paying through alternative methods (such as a bank wire), additional information is required. We collect that information in order to:
Verify your identity for payment authorization
Ship your order to you
Contact you regarding your order status
Personalize your shopping experience
Send you helpful information from Sarraf Jewelry and,
Generate anonymous statistics.
Your personal information will be shared with your credit card company and the party through whom your product is shipped. This shared personal information includes all the following:
your name
your e-mail address
your street address
your telephone number
Your personal information will not be sold to mailing-list firms or distributed to any of Sarraf Jewelry's partners without your permission. Although we may occasionally share statistics about our customers with important business partners, we do not disclose any identifying information about individual customers. If you elect to participate in a Sarraf Jewelry promotion (contest or sweepstakes), we will share your personal information with those organizations in order to ensure redemption of that promotion with the third-party partner managing that promotion. Further, Sarraf Jewelry provides you with access to third party partners to provide you certain services . If you decide to utilize these types of third party services , you will be directed to that third party's application. Sarraf Jewelry will provide that third party with your transaction information and then that third party will collect the additional information it needs in order to provide you with the requested service. Any information that you provide directly to that third party in connection with such services is covered by the privacy practices of such third party. Sarraf Jewelry is in no way responsible for the data collected or the privacy practices of any third party. You may want to consult the privacy policies of a third party prior to providing that third party with your address or other identifying information.
Updating Personal Information
If the personal information we've gathered from you changes or you no longer desire our service, we will gladly correct, update, or remove any personal data you have previously provided to us. To request a change or removal of your personal information, send e-mail to service@sarraf.com or contact one of our customer service associates at 888-472-7723.
Secure Server
When you place an order with Sarraf Jewelry, you will be using our secure server. Our secure server software encrypts all of the personal information you submit to us. This helps to maintain the confidentiality of your information.
Cookies
"Cookies" are small pieces of information that are stored by your browser on your computer hard drive. You must have cookies enabled in order for you to be able to perform many of the general functions on the Sarraf Jewelry Web site. With cookies enabled, the Sarraf Jewelry Web site will have the capacity to deliver you a more customized and complete shopping experience, to track visits from our affiliates and partners, and to enable the use of our shopping cart. We do not use cookies to store or collect any personal information such as names, addresses, or payment information. If you remove our cookie from your hard drive, you will not be able to complete a search or a purchase on our site. To learn how to enable cookies on your computer, visit the Web site that corresponds to the browser you use:
Microsoft Internet Explorer
Netscape Navigator
IP Address
We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server, to administer and tune the operation of our site, and to log your browser type and referring URL information. Your IP address may also be used in collecting statistical data or in gathering broad usage information. Certain parts of this information may be shared with our partners, but your personal information will not be distributed.
Changes in Privacy Policy
If we modify this privacy policy, we will post a notice on our Web site.
Opt Out of Receiving Communications
To opt out of receiving communications from Sarraf Jewelry, you can make your request in person by contacting a customer service associate at 888-472-7723 or by e-mail at service@sarraf.com.
Fraud Protection
If a third party obtains your personal information from a purchase made with us and uses that information to perpetrate credit card fraud, you are protected. Under the Fair Credit Billing Act, your bank may hold you liable for $50 of fraudulent charges. If your bank holds you liable for any portion of the $50, Sarraf Jewelry Inc. will cover up to the entire $50.*
Contacting Us
If you have questions about this privacy statement, please contact our customer service department at service@sarraf.com or at 888-472-7723.
* Sarraf Jewelry will cover this liability if the unauthorized use resulted through no fault of yours from purchases made on Sarraf Jewelry's secure server. In the event of unauthorized use of your credit card, you must notify your credit card company in accordance with its reporting rules and procedures.
×
×
What is a Gold?
Gold is durable, sturdy, dependable, and makes an ideal setting for your precious diamond jewelry. Gold also comes in a variety of colors -- yellow, white, and rose (or pink).
The karatage of the jewelry will tell you what percentage of gold it contains: 24 karat is 100 percent, 18 karat is 75 percent, and 14 karat is 58.5 percent gold. When comparing gold jewelry, the higher the number of karats, the greater the value.
When buying gold jewelry, always look for the karat mark. All other things being equal, the higher the karat, the more expensive the piece. In the United States, 14-karat gold, or 585 parts pure gold, is the most common degree of fineness. Nothing less than 10 karats can legally be marked or sold as gold jewelry in the U.S. However, lower karatages, such as 8-karat gold and 9-karat gold, are popular in other countries
Approximate Metal Weight is intended use is for you to have an indication of Approximate weight of the metal. While being accurate is very important to us at Sarraf.com, due to factors beyond our control it is impossible to be exact each and every time, therefore we strive to maintain an accuracy of ± 5%.
What is a 925 Sterling silver?
In its pure form silver is almost as soft as gold, and therefore is usually alloyed with copper for strength. Karatage is not marked because, legally, anything called "silver" or "sterling silver" is 92.5% pure.
Fine Silver in its natural state, 999/1000 pure, is too soft an element for practical jewelry. To make it workable, an alloy such as copper is added. Here are the main silver alloys. Sterling Silver is a mixture of 92.5 % pure silver (925 parts) and 7.5 % metal alloy.
What is a carat?
"Carat Weight" is simply the weight of the diamond.
By definition, 1 carat is exactly 200 milligrams.
Since most diamonds sold in the jewelry industry weigh less than 1 carat, the carat is usually subdivided into "points."
There are 100 points in 1 carat, so that a diamond weighing 3/4 carat would be a "75 point diamond."
In summary:
1 carat = 200 milligrams = 100 points
Why is carat weight important and how it effects the price?
Carat is the simplest and most objective of the four C's. A 1.00 Carat diamond weighs 0.2 gm on scales weighs. In the trade we call 1/2ct - 50 points.
Naturally more Carat weight means more cost because BIG diamonds are very rare. A diamond of double the weight costs around 4 times more. Add the magic weight idea to rarity: a 1.00ct D color Flawless costs 1.7 times more than a 99 point D Flawless.
Diamonds are graded on a letter scale from D to Z: D, E, or F diamonds have no color detectable to the unaided eye;
grad G, H, I, or J are nearly colorless, but a trained gemologist can detect a slight yellow cast. J through Z colored diamonds have yellow or gray color visible to the unaided eye. Diamonds rated lower than I have color that is detectable even to the untrained eye. Those rated J to M have a trace of color, while any diamond with an N or higher carries a noticeable yellow tint
The charts above are clarity plots, which is a representation of the number and size of inclusions typically present in diamonds of a particular clarity grade. Look for a clarity plot on a diamond certificate, or grading report, to get a clear idea of the number and size of inclusions in a particular diamond. From this map, you can perfectly determine a diamond's clarity without even
Clarity determination factors
Gemologists use grades of clarity to describe how many inclusions a diamond has. These grades range from flawless (FL) or internally flawless (IF) to included (I3), with the numbers indicating varying degrees of quality within a grade (1 being the best).
Most commonly diamond sold are diamond that has no inclusions visible to the unaided eye, like VS1 and SI1-2. Diamonds of this clarity are much less expensive than flawless diamonds, and will not contain inclusions that would reduce from the splendor of the diamond
MM
Inches
Inches
MM
Inches
Inches
1
0.04
2 inches
For comparison purposes, here are the Thickness measurements of some common US coins:
In order To get clearer understanding of how thick or wide is a piece of jewelry, you can use US coins for reference. For thicker items you can stack multiple coins to acquire the approximate thickness or the width of your selected jewelry.
Dime Thickness is 1.35mm and Diameter is 17.9mm
Penny Thickness is 1.55mm and Diameter is 19.05mm
Nickel Thickness is 1.95mm and Diameter is 21.21mm
Quarter Thickness is 1.75mm and Diameter is 24.26mm
